Jeff Ashear

Full Stack Developer

Spokane, Washington

303.898.3638

kinesthesiac@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-ashear

GitHub: https://github.com/Jeff-Ashear

Portfolio: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/PersonalPortfolio/

Career Summary

Life-long learner with a master's in composition, pursuing a full-time position in full stack or front end web development. Experience with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap JS, Jquery, Node, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, MongoDB, and React. Award-winning composer with relevant experience creating object programming-based virtual instruments, sound-sculpture and installations.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.JS, Express, APIs, Handlebars, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, React, Postman, GIT, GitHub, Heroku, REST, JSON.

Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

Superior knowledge of music. Proficient researcher.

Applications Built

Sproso: https://echo2project2.herokuapp.com/

- -Full stack MERN app with a robust database structure. Provides game-ified social goal tracking for staying connected during stay at home.
- -Creator and lead developer. Uses MySQL, React.js, React Bootstrap, custom CSS animations, Axios, and the DoppelMe API.

Google Books Search: https://googlebooksapisearchapp.herokuapp.com/

- -Light weight MERN stack app allowing the user to search Google Books using its api to see relevant info, view and purchase externally, and save it to a database.
- -Solo project. MongoDB, Mongoose, MLab, Axios, React.js, React Bootstrap

gamer.Ready: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/gamer.Ready/

- -A fan hub and market research tool, makes persistent commonly searched-for data about released and upcoming games.
- -Creator and lead developer. -Full stack work. Uses Javascript, Bootstrap, JQ, ajax, JSON, APIs from RAWG, OGDB, YouTube.

Trivia Game: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/AdvancedTriviaGame/

- -A simple game using dynamic content populated by both timers and user input.
- -Solo project. -Uses HTML5, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, and GitHub.

Experience

Self-Employed / Composer

2009 - Present, Denver, CO

Compose and rehearse professionally commissioned musics for small groups of orchestral instruments and active/interactive electronic systems. Pieces performed locally, nationally, and internationally. Development of custom software tools for making virtual instruments, electronic installations, and specialized sound-sculpture for the concert hall.

Self-Employed/ Classical Guitarist

2005 - 2009, Bozeman, MT

Prepared and performed intricate repertoire for both solo and ensemble concertizing. Instructed students of various ages and ability levels in guitar technique and performance, as well as music theory.

Montana State University/ Recording Engineer

1999-2006, Bozeman, MT

Engineered, recorded, edited, published, and archived concerts, recitals, and professional studio projects. Experience with studio and concert hall recording equipment and software. Managed complex software and hardware environments.

Education

University of Denver / Coding Bootcamp

November 2019 - May 2020, Denver, CO

Certificate course covering full stack web development and methods for continued study.

University of Denver / Masters of Music, Composition

September 2009 - June 2012, Denver, CO

Developed my own path of independent study to incorporate digital tools into modern concert music creation. Softwares include Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

Montana State University, Bozeman / Bachelor of Arts

September 1999 - June 2005, Bozeman, MT

Specialization in classical guitar performance, recording engineering and composition.

Awards

2010-Present: multiple competition awards for new works of music

2011: DU Outstanding Composer, Lamont School of Music

DU Playground Commission Award, Lamont School of Music

2005: MSU Community Service Award

MSU Award for Excellence